https://www.fostercarecooperative.co.uk/privacy-policy/

Skip to content
Privacy
We take your privacy seriously
We believe in safeguarding the privacy of our users while providing a personalised and beneficial service. This Privacy Policy Statement explains our policiesIf you have any requests or queries at any time concerning your personal information or our practices, please email duty@fostercarecooperative.co.uk or write to us at Penny Hall, The Haysfield, Spring Lane North, Malvern, Worcs WR14 1GF.What information do we collect?We collect personal information from you when you fill in an enquiry form, complete a download form.We also collect information automatically about your visits to our site, such as browsing patterns. However information collected in this way is only used in aggregate form rather than being linked to identifiable individuals.How do we use it?We use personal information collected via fostercarecooperative.co.uk in the following ways:To process your enquiry and provide the most appropriate response.We may also use information in aggregate form to help us analyse, develop and manage the site.Please be assured that users’ information submitted via forms will be treated as confidential and won’t be passed on to third parties. Cookies – What are they and how do we use them?Cookies are bits of electronic information that a web site can transfer to your hard drive to help tailor and keep records of your visit to that site. Cookies allow us to customise your visits to this site to your individual preferences, helping us provide you with the best possible service on our site. Most major web sites use cookies and their use is standard on the Internet. Most internet browsers automatically accept cookies but you can change your settings so that you are notified whenever you are sent a cookie. LinksThis website may contain links to other sites. Please note that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of other sites. We recommend you read the privacy statements on entering other sites. This privacy statement applies only to information collected by this website.Public Notice – FCC Privacy Policy For CCTV Camera UseThe fitting, impact and implementation of the CCTV cameras in all FCC premises is to ensure security cover for our buildings and the sensitive data and equipment they house. This is achieved either by the deterrence of fully operational CCTV cameras or effective intruder image recording if the deterrence fails.  The recording is not retained beyond 30 days unless there is incident information required for investigation or evidential purposes.The external cameras are fixed and specifically sited to cover the entrances of FCC premises and shielded “blind spots” (areas that are not open to public access) around the periphery of all FCC buildings. They are day/night (infrared) capable.Data is securely stored on the recording machine within the computer room at Malvern. This is a hard disk system in an interior room with controlled access.  The system automatically overwrites recordings after 30 days.  No additional copies are held.Interior cameras are movement activated and focussed on the main working area and provide additional alarm capability to the fitted intruder alarm system. They are in operation outside normal working hours and are internally focussed. Out of hours all shutters are down and no external views are possible. They are day/night (infrared) capable. The images are stored on a remote internet storage capability for 30 days.The view is restricted to the FCC premises with the exception of some road coverage on the periphery of the cameras due to their necessary location to fulfil their main security function.In the unlikely case that ‘passer-by’ images are captured, or partially captured, they are not retained, shared or accessed beyond those with security/CCTV access within FCC. Individuals concerned about possible image/data capture should contact duty@fostercarecooperative.co.uk, relating the date, time and location of concern. This will be treated as a Subject Access Request which we would request, supported by an identifiable image of the applicant. Any image request beyond 30 days cannot be fulfilled as no archive images are retained.Changes to our policyWe reserve the right to make changes to our Privacy Policy, and we will post those changes on this page. Please review this page on a regular basis for changes. We will use information in accordance with the Privacy Policy Statement under which the information was collected.
Accessibility
Maethu-gyda-FCC
Privacy Policy
Work for us
Facebook
Twitter
Menu
Accessibility
Maethu-gyda-FCC
Privacy Policy
Work for us
Facebook
Twitter
Copyright 2020 – The Foster Care Co-operative | A company registered in England and Wales, No. 3861213.  |  If you require assistance with reading any text, please call 01684 892380
Close Menu
Making a fostering enquiry
We’re looking for caring people who can make a real difference to children’s lives.The initial basic criteria for becoming a foster carer is:• To be aged 18 or over (there is no upper age limit!)• To have at least one spare bedroom in your home available for fostering.Final approval will be based on an assessment, medical and background checks.Click below to make a no-obligation enquiry!
Apply Now
